Brotherhood of Locomotive Firemen and Enginemen Records 5141
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Brotherhood of Locomotive Firemen and Enginemen Records
1875-1975
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Brotherhood of Locomotive Firemen and Enginemen (BLF&E)
5141
201.22 cubic feet
201.2 linear ft.
Newsletters, correspondence, proceedings, case files, minutes (administrative records).
Bulletins, correspondence, convention proceedings, arbitration, grievance, and subject files, meeting minutes, union publications, and ephemera relating to the BLFE, labor relations in the railroad industry in the United States, and railroad labor issues from the late 19th through the mid-20th centuries.
3338461
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183 kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
CE & CB, January 28, 2012
EAD encoding:
Kheel Staff, March 07, 2019
Biographical / Historical
The Brotherhood of Locomotive Firemen was founded on December 1, 1873, at Port Jervis, New York, to provide mutual support for railroad firemen. The Brotherhood initially emphasized insurance, but by the late nineteenth century had branched out into labor-management relations.
At the turn of the century, the organization changed its name to the Brotherhood of Locomotive Firemen and Enginemen (BLFE) after permitting engineers to join its ranks. In 1969, the union merged with the Order of Railway Conductors and Brakemen, the Brotherhood of Railroad Trainmen, and the Switchmen's Union of North America to form the United Transportation Union.
Scope and Contents
Bulletins, correspondence, convention proceedings, arbitration, grievance, and subject files, meeting minutes, union publications, and ephemera relating to the BLFE, labor relations in the railroad industry in the United States, and railroad labor issues from the late 19th through the mid-20th centuries.
Among the most significant topics covered in the collection are labor disputes, working conditions, and strikes in the railroad industry; railroad law and legislation, particularly at the state level; and black employees in the railroad industry.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Related Materials
Related Collections: 5141 G: Brotherhood of Locomotive Firemen and Enginemen Graphics 5141 MB: Brotherhood of Locomotive Firemen and Enginemen Memorabilia 5141 P: Brotherhood of Locomotive Firemen and Enginemen Photographs 5176: Grand Lodge of the Ladies Society of the Former Brotherhood of Locomotive Firemen and Enginemen Records 5467: Brotherhood of Locomotive Firemen and Enginemen Local 807 (Auburn, NY) Records 5475: Brotherhood of Locomotive Firemen and Enginemen General Chairman, Boston and Maine Railroad Records 5611: Brotherhood of Locomotive Firemen and Enginemen Honorary Register of Disabled 5646: Brotherhood of Locomotive Firemen and Enginemen Additional Records 5869: Brotherhood of Locomotive Firemen and Enginemen Local 807 (Auburn, NY) Additional Records 6176: Brotherhood of Locomotive Firemen and Enginemen Additional Records
Railroads -- Employees -- Labor unions -- United States; Collective bargaining -- Railroads -- United States; Grievance procedures -- United States; Railroad law -- United States; Labor disputes -- United States; Strikes and lockouts -- Railroads -- United States; Arbitration, Industrial -- United States; African Americans -- Employment; Railroads -- Employees -- United States; Brotherhood of Locomotive Firemen and Enginemen; Brotherhood of Locomotive Firemen (U.S.)
3338461
- Index - both alphabetical and numerical by file number (Box 1, Folder 1)
  Scope and Contents
  2 volumes
- Index - Alphabetical by Railroad (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Index - Alphabetical by Subject (Box 3, Folder 1)
- 1-23. (Box 4, Folder 1)
- 24-54 (Box 5, Folder 1)
- 55-84 (Box 6, Folder 1)
- 85-114 (Box 7, Folder 1)
- 115-132 (Box 8, Folder 1)
- 133-150 (Box 9, Folder 1)
- 151-173 (Box 10, Folder 1)
- 174-200 (Box 11, Folder 1)
- 201-220 (Box 12, Folder 1)
- 221-239 (Box 13, Folder 1)
- 240-256 (Box 14, Folder 1)
- 257-268 (Box 15, Folder 1)
- 269-287 (Box 16, Folder 1)
- 288-293 (Box 17, Folder 1)
- 294-313 (Box 18, Folder 1)
- 314-345 (Box 19, Folder 1)
- 346-373 (Box 20, Folder 1)
- 374-387 (Box 21, Folder 1)
- 388-411 (Box 22, Folder 1)
- 412-433 (Box 23, Folder 1)
- 434-452 (Box 24, Folder 1)
- 453-469 (Box 25, Folder 1)
- 470-486 (Box 26, Folder 1)
- 487-502 (Box 27, Folder 1)
- 503-526 (Box 28, Folder 1)
- 527-549 (Box 29, Folder 1)
- 550-570 (Box 30, Folder 1)
- 571-591 (Box 31, Folder 1)
- 592-599 (Box 32, Folder 1)
- 599A-601 (Box 33, Folder 1)
- 602-620 (Box 34, Folder 1)
- 621-636 (Box 35, Folder 1)
- 637-648 (Box 36, Folder 1)
- 649-666 (Box 37, Folder 1)
- 667-688 (Box 38, Folder 1)
- 689-700 (Box 39, Folder 1)
- 701-717 (Box 40, Folder 1)
- 718-739 (Box 41, Folder 1)
- 740-763 (Box 42, Folder 1)
- 764-780 (Box 43, Folder 1)
- 780A-797 (Box 44, Folder 1)
- 798-824 (Box 45, Folder 1)
- 825-847 (Box 46, Folder 1)
- 848-870 (Box 47, Folder 1)
- 871-891 (Box 48, Folder 1)
- 892-906 (Box 49, Folder 1)
- 907-928 (Box 50, Folder 1)
- 929-946 (Box 51, Folder 1)
- 947-973 (Box 52, Folder 1)
- 974-988 (Box 53, Folder 1)
- 989-1002 (Box 54, Folder 1)
- 1003-1014 (Box 55, Folder 1)
- 1015-1023 (Box 56, Folder 1)
- 1024-1045 (Box 57, Folder 1)
- 1046-1061 (Box 58, Folder 1)
- 1062-1074 (Box 59, Folder 1)
- 1075-1085 (Box 60, Folder 1)
- 1086-1097 (Box 61, Folder 1)
- 1098-1119 (Box 62, Folder 1)
- 1120-1146 (Box 63, Folder 1)
- 1147-1169 (Box 64, Folder 1)
- 1170-1195 (Box 65, Folder 1)
- 1196-1208 (Box 66, Folder 1)
- 1209-1224 (Box 67, Folder 1)
- 1225-1250 (Box 68, Folder 1)
- 1251-1272 (Box 69, Folder 1)
- 1273-1291 (Box 70, Folder 1)
- 1292-1314 (Box 71, Folder 1)
- 1315-1335 (Box 72, Folder 1)
- 1336-1352 (Box 73, Folder 1)
- 1352-1367 (Box 74, Folder 1)
- 1368-1388 (Box 75, Folder 1)
- 1389-1408 (Box 76, Folder 1)
- 1409-1433 (Box 77, Folder 1)
- 1434-1454 (Box 78, Folder 1)
- 1455-1466 (Box 79, Folder 1)
- 1467-1481 (Box 80, Folder 1)
- 1482-1501 (Box 81, Folder 1)
- 1502-1518 (Box 82, Folder 1)
- 1519-1543 (Box 83, Folder 1)
- 1544-1555 (Box 84, Folder 1)
- 1556-1568 (Box 85, Folder 1)
- 1569-1588 (Box 86, Folder 1)
- 1589-1609 (Box 87, Folder 1)
- 1610-1632 (Box 88, Folder 1)
- 1633-1651A (Box 89, Folder 1)
- 1651B-1669 (Box 90, Folder 1)
- 1670-1686 (Box 91, Folder 1)
- 1687-1702 (Box 92, Folder 1)
- 1703-1717 (Box 93, Folder 1)
- 1718-1737 (Box 94, Folder 1)
- 1738-1749 (Box 95, Folder 1)
- 1750-1761 (Box 96, Folder 1)
- 1762-1778 (Box 97, Folder 1)
- 1779-1796 (Box 98, Folder 1)
- 1797-1815 (Box 99, Folder 1)
- 1816-1830 (Box 100, Folder 1)
- 1831-1845 (Box 101, Folder 1)
- 1846-1859 (Box 102, Folder 1)
- 1860-1875 (Box 103, Folder 1)
- 1876-1891 (Box 104, Folder 1)
- 1892-1913 (Box 105, Folder 1)
- 1914-1930 (Box 106, Folder 1)
- 1931-1946 (Box 107, Folder 1)
- 1947-1961 (Box 108, Folder 1)
- 1962-1975 (Box 109, Folder 1)
- 1976-1985 (Box 110, Folder 1)
- 1986-2000 (Box 111, Folder 1)
- 2001-2014 (Box 112, Folder 1)
- 2015-2023 (Box 113, Folder 1)
- 2024-2033 (Box 114, Folder 1)
- 2034-2044 (Box 115, Folder 1)
- 2045-2055 (Box 116, Folder 1)
- 2056-2068 (Box 117, Folder 1)
- 2069-2074 (Box 118, Folder 1)
- 2075-2092 (Box 119, Folder 1)
- 2093-2106 (Box 120, Folder 1)
- 2107-2117 (Box 121, Folder 1)
- 2118-2130 (Box 122, Folder 1)
- 2131-2140 (Box 123, Folder 1)
- 2141-2154 (Box 124, Folder 1)
- 2155-2167 (Box 125, Folder 1)
- 2168-2173 (Box 126, Folder 1)
- 2174-2184 (Box 127, Folder 1)
- 2185-2193 (Box 128, Folder 1)
- 2194-2204 (Box 129, Folder 1)
- 2205-2212 (Box 130, Folder 1)
- 2215-2221 (Box 131, Folder 1)
- 2222-2228 (Box 132, Folder 1)
- Board of Directors Wage Commission Files (Box 133, Folder 1)
- Board of Directors Wage Commission Files (Box 134, Folder 1)
- Board of Directors Wage Commission Files (Box 135, Folder 1)
- Board of Directors Wage Commission Files (Box 136, Folder 1)
- Board of Directors Wage Commission Files (Box 137, Folder 1)
- Board of Directors Finance Committee Files (Box 138, Folder 1)
- Board of Directors Resume of Decisions Rendered (Box 139, Folder 1)
- Board of Directors Monthly Asset Statements, 1946-1968 (Box 140, Folder 1)
  Assignment to Positions and Rate Classifications
- Board of Directors Reports of Board of Director's (Bound. Volumes.) (Box 141, Folder 1)
- Board of Directors Reports of Board of Director's (Bound. Volumes.) (Box 142, Folder 1)
- Board of Directors Reports of Board of Director's (Bound. Volumes.) (Box 143, Folder 1)
- Board of Directors Reports of Board of Director's (Bound. Volumes.) (Box 144, Folder 1)
- Board of Directors files, 1926-1968 (Box 145, Folder 1)
  Convention City File, 1952; Laws Pertaining to the Bound. of Director's; Minutes, 1968; Schedule of Wages and Working Conditions, 1964; volume containing disability claim dispositions by the Board of Directors, 1926-1931
- Includes very early Eugene V. Debs correspondence; large amount of Railway Labor Executive's Association (RLEA) correspondence (Box 146, Folder 1)
- Includes very early Eugene V. Debs correspondence; large amount of Railway Labor Executive's Association (RLEA) correspondence (Box 147, Folder 1)
- President's Official Circulars and Bulletins, 1913-1953 (Box 147.1, Folder 1)
  (5 volumes) 3 volumes include an index at the beginning of the volume; 1 volume re Amalgamation.
- President's Official Circulars and Bulletins, 1913-1953 (Box 147.2, Folder 1)
- Ballots (Box 148, Folder 1)
- General Correspondence, 1965 (Box 148, Folder 2)
- Correspondence - New Organization, 1965 (Box 148, Folder 3)
- General Correspondence - New Organization, 1967 (Box 148, Folder 4)
- AFL-CIO File, 1966-1967 (Box 148, Folder 5)
- Washington Job Protection Agreement (Box 148, Folder 6)
- Amalgamation, 1949 and Circular (Box 148, Folder 7)
- CPA File, 1966-1968 (Box 148, Folder 8)
- Dr. J.J. Kaufman, Correspondence, 1966 (Box 148, Folder 9)
- Ladies Organization - New Union Correspondence, 1967 (Box 148, Folder 10)
- Jean Conrad - Correspondence, 1966-1967 (Box 148, Folder 11)
- Committee of Three - Sequence of Events, 1966 (Box 148, Folder 12)
- Umbrella Plan (Box 148, Folder 13)
- SUNA insurance and pension plans (Box 148, Folder 14)
- New Organization Information Payment of Pensions, 1966 (Box 148, Folder 15)
- 30-Man Committee, 1966-1967 (Box 148, Folder 16)
- CPA Reports re 3 way merger, 1966-1967 (Box 148, Folder 17)
- Pensions, new (Box 148, Folder 18)
- Rough Draft File, 1966 (Box 148, Folder 19)
- SUNA, Misc. material, 1966-1967 (Box 148, Folder 20)
- New Organization, ORC & B, BLF & E, SUNA Source materials (Box 148, Folder 21)
- (Extra copies) NMB R-2444 RED (AFL) PRR, 1951 (Box 148, Folder 22)
  18814
- Committee of Three Letter, 1966 (Box 148, Folder 23)
  5/12/66 (extra copies)
- Canada - extra copies (Box 148, Folder 24)
- Extra copies, officers and employees (Box 148, Folder 25)
- Extra copies, directory listings (Box 148, Folder 26)
- Insurance (extra copies) (Box 148, Folder 27)
- Legislation, 1966-1967 (Box 148, Folder 28)
  Correspondence
- Memo 3, Active Members by RR, 1967 (Box 148, Folder 29)
- Memo 4, ORC & B, BLF & E, SUNA, Gen. Adjustment Committee (Box 148, Folder 30)
- Sequence of Events re Unification Committee of three, 1966 (Box 148, Folder 31)
- Memo 1, Officers correspondence (Box 148, Folder 32)
- Memo 2, Office employees (adjustments), 1967 (Box 148, Folder 33)
- Memo 5, Unification-Finances of the ORC&B, BLF&E, SUNA, 1967 (Box 148, Folder 34)
- Memo 6, Unification - first division, NRAB (Box 148, Folder 35)
- Memo 7, Unification - Change in representation to the new Union (Box 148, Folder 36)
- Memo 8, Pensions - Officers, 1967 (Box 148, Folder 37)
- Memo 9, Canadian Autonomy, 1967 (Box 148, Folder 38)
- Memo 10, Change in representation-Canada, 1967 (Box 148, Folder 39)
  24613
- Memo 11, AFL-CIO Affiliation, 1967 (Box 148, Folder 40)
- Memo 12, ORC&B, BLF&E Insurance Merger, 1967 (Box 148, Folder 41a)
- American Railway Union Constitution, 1967 (Box 148, Folder 42-44)
- Approved Drafts Book 1 and 2 (Box 148, Folder 45)
- American Railway Union Agreement (Box 148, Folder 46)
- Implementation Agreement (Canada) (Box 148, Folder 47-48)
- Unification Agreement, 1967 (Box 148, Folder 49)
  (Rough Draft #7) 4/7/67
- Canada-Misc. (Box 148, Folder 50)
- Combined Directories, BLF&E, SUNA AND ORC&B (Box 148, Folder 51)
- Railway Clerks, Staff Retirement Trust Fund, Report. of Exam, 1965 (Box 149, Folder 52)
- Rough Draft No. 6, April 8, 1967, Penalties (Box 149, Folder 53)
- Implementation Agreement, ARU, 1967 (Box 149, Folder 54)
  24476
- Certification Certificates, Canada, 1967 (Box 149, Folder 55)
  24607
- Contract and Agreement of Merger, Mutual Benefit Dept., 1964 (Box 149, Folder 56)
  6/26/64
- American Railway Union (background information), 1967 (Box 149, Folder 57)
- Combined Directory (Box 149, Folder 58)
- Merger - Financial Information and SUNA Convention, 1967 (Box 149, Folder 59)
- New Organization, Gen. Correspondence. and rough drafts, 1967 (Box 149, Folder 60)
- American Railway Union, 1968 (Box 149, Folder 61)
  organized 1/1/68, proposed ballot
- Implementation Agreement, ARU (Box 149, Folder 62)
- Declaration of Principles to Implement Unification (Box 149, Folder 64)
- Unification, first proposal (Box 149, Folder 65)
- Amalgamation, Order of Sleeping Gar Conductors with the ORC, 1962 (Box 149, Folder 66)
- Constitutions, combined directories, RLA (Box 149, Folder 67)
- Merger Agreements, other unions (Box 149, Folder 68)
- Report to Chief Executives, 1966 (Box 149, Folder 69)
- Officers (Box 149, Folder 70)
- Employees (Box 149, Folder 71)
- Dues, 1966 (Box 149, Folder 72)
- Misc. memos, 1967 (Box 149, Folder 73)
- Insurance (Box 149, Folder 74)
- First Div., NRAB (Box 149, Folder 75)
- National Mediation Board. (Box 149, Folder 76)
- Correspondence. re Ideas, 1966 (Box 149, Folder 77)
- BLF&E Board. of Directors, Coat (Box 149, Folder 78)
- U.S. Dept. of Labor (Box 149, Folder 79)
- Railroad Retirement Act (Box 149, Folder 80)
- ORC - OSCC (Box 149, Folder 82)
- Public Law 86-257, Landrum Griffin Act (Box 149, Folder 83)
- Rough Draft, No. 2, Implementation Agreement, 1966 (Box 149, Folder 84)
  24442
- BLF&E Plan of Amalgamation-Merger Agreement (Box 149, Folder 85)
- Certification Certificates (Box 149, Folder 86)
- Unification, Rough Drafts of Constitutions (Box 149, Folder 87)
- Directory, 1/1/67, 1967 (Box 149, Folder 88)
- Declaration of Principles (Box 149, Folder 89)
- Articles, Part I, Approved Drafts (Box 149, Folder 90)
- Weighted Voting (Box 149, Folder 91)
- Emblem (Unification), Photos (Box 149, Folder 92)
- Coe College Assistance, 1967 (Box 149, Folder 93)
- Insurance Merger, 1967 (Box 149, Folder 94)
- Letters accompanying constitutions of various unions, In chronological order. (Box 149, Folder 95)
- Unification, NLRB (Box 149, Folder 96)
- New Organization, Informative releases, 1966-1967 (Box 149, Folder 97)
- Financial statements. BLF&E (Box 149, Folder 98)
- Active Members, by railroad, 1966 (Box 149, Folder 99)
- Combined - Directory (Box 149, Folder 100)
- Newspaper clipping (BRT propaganda), 1966 (Box 149, Folder 101)
- Unification, first div., NRAB (Box 150, Folder 102)
- National Labor Rel. Board. (Box 150, Folder 103)
- Constitution of the American Railway Union, Pt. I & II (Box 150, Folder 104-105)
- Proposed 4-way Merger, ER1ST & ERNST, 1968-1969 (Box 150, Folder 106)
- General Correspondence, 1968 (Box 150, Folder 107)
- Proposed officers and Board. of Directors (Box 150, Folder 108)
- Letters - Pro Anti-Unification (Box 150, Folder 109)
- Merging of the Four Insurance Departments. (Box 150, Folder 110)
- Local Lodge Information (Box 150, Folder 111)
- Railway Labor's Political League (Box 150, Folder 112)
- Political Education League, BRT, 1968 (Box 150, Folder 113)
- Report of Finance Committee, 1968 (Box 150, Folder 114)
- Monthly Report, BRT, 1968 (Box 150, Folder 115)
  24910
- M-300 Number of Employees, 1967-1968 (Box 150, Folder 116)
  11/67-3/68
- BRT Membership, 1968 (Box 150, Folder 117)
- BLF&E Contracts (Box 150, Folder 118)
- State Legislation (Box 150, Folder 119)
- UTU, Canada, 1968-1969 (Box 150, Folder 120)
  General Correspondence
- Proposal of Merger of BRAC and TCU (Box 150, Folder 121)
- Committee of Ten, 1968 (Box 150, Folder 122)
- Legal Opinion on Unification, 1968 (Box 150, Folder 123-124)
- General Grievance Committee balances (Box 150, Folder 125)
- Unification - Official Directory, 1968 (Box 150, Folder 126)
- Ballots - Eligibility to Receive, 1968 (Box 150, Folder 127)
- Proposed Unification Agreement, UTU (Box 150, Folder 128)
- Bids Covering Purchase of Annuity Contracts, 1968 (Box 150, Folder 129)
- Unification - Pro Rata Cost (Box 150, Folder 130)
- Unification - Letterheads, 1968 (Box 150, Folder 131)
- Unification - Press Kit (Box 150, Folder 132)
- Translation of Constitution (Canada, French) (Box 150, Folder 133)
- Unification - Final Agreement (Box 150, Folder 134)
- Copy of Final Unification Agreement (Box 150, Folder 135)
- Attachments: Extra copies, Membership Statistics, Folder A (Box 150, Folder 136)
- Attachments: Membership Statistics, Folder B (Box 150, Folder 137)
- Committee of Four Addresses (Box 150, Folder 138)
- Pro Forma Balance Sheet, UTU, Cleveland, Ohio, 1968 (Box 150, Folder 139)
  25203
- Personal, Memos on Unification, 1968 (Box 150, Folder 140)
- Miscellaneous Agreements and correspondence, 1968 (Box 150, Folder 141)
- Local Mine, Mill 598 vs. United Steelworkers case, 1968 (Box 150, Folder 142)
- Brotherhood of Railroad Trainmen Officer's Birthdates (Box 151, Folder 143)
- Unification Agreement, Attachment No, 1 (Box 151, Folder 144)
- Consolidation of Locals (American Railway Union) (Box 151, Folder 145)
- Amending Constitution, Misc. (Box 151, Folder 146)
- 10-Man Unification Committee Proposals (Box 151, Folder 147)
- BLF&E Field Staff Meeting, Cleveland, Ohio, 10/8-9/68 (Box 151, Folder 148)
- 40-Man Committee - Legislative Convention (Box 151, Folder 149)
- Preservation of Craft Autonomy, Amendments (Box 151, Folder 150)
- Mergers, Leases, Coordinations, etc. Article 90 (Box 151, Folder 151)
- Committees of Adjustment, Article 82 (Box 151, Folder 152)
- Membership Directory (Box 151, Folder 153)
- Proposals for Signature (Box 151, Folder 154)
- Pension Plan for BRT and Employee Booklet Text (Box 151, Folder 155)
- Article 1-57, corrected copy (Box 151, Folder 156)
- Articles 58-101, corrected (Box 151, Folder 157)
- Chronological Index to Proceedings of Unification and Constitutionals (Box 151, Folder 158)
- Convention Constitution (Box 151, Folder 159)
- Unification documentation (Box 151, Folder 160-161)
- Constitutional documents (Box 151, Folder 162-163)
- Committee Proposals (Box 151, Folder 164)
- American Railway Union Constitution (Box 151, Folder 165)
- Proposed Unification Agreement (Box 151, Folder 166)
- Proceedings of Unification Convention, 1968 (Box 151, Folder 167-176)
- 10-Man Unification Committee - Rough Draft (Box 151, Folder 177)
- Unification Agreement, Sections Not Agreed To (Box 151, Folder 178)
- Minutes of the Committee, 1932-1971 (Box 152, Folder 1)
- Minutes of the Committee, 1932-1971 (Box 153, Folder 1)
- Minutes of the Committee, 1932-1971 (Box 154, Folder 1)
- Minutes of the Committee (Box 155, Folder 1)
- Minutes of the Finance Committee from Sept. 10, 1959 to July 3, 1963, Mr. Phillips, 1959-1963 (Box 156, Folder 10)
- Minutes of the Finance Committee from Jan. 6, 1954 to July 9, 1959, Mr. Phillips, 1954-1959 (Box 156, Folder 9)
- Minutes of the Finance Committee from Jan. 27, 1950 to Sept. 3, 1953, Mr. Phillips, 1950-1953 (Box 156, Folder 8)
- Minutes of the Finance Committee from July 18, 1945 to Aug. 8, 1949, Mr. Phillips, 1945-1949 (Box 156, Folder 7)
- Minutes of the Finance Committee from March 3, 1941 to Feb. 23, 1945, Mr. Phillips, 1941-1945 (Box 156, Folder 6)
- Minutes of the Finance Committee from Dec. 4, 1939 to March 6, 1941 and Index, Mr. Phillips, 1939-1941 (Box 156, Folder 5)
- Minutes of the Finance Committee from Jan. 28, 1938 to Oct. 10, 1939 and Index, Mr. Phillips, 1938-1939 (Box 156, Folder 4)
- Minutes of the Finance Committee from Jan. 30, 1936 to Oct. 9, 1937 and Index, Mr. Phillips, 1936-1937 (Box 156, Folder 3)
- Minutes of the Finance Committee from Jan. 8, 1935 to Oct. 10, 1935 and Index, Mr. Phillips (Box 156, Folder 2)
- Minutes of the Finance Committee from Jan. 7, 1932 to Sept. 29, 1934 and Index, Mr. Phillips, 1932-1934 (Box 156, Folder 1)
- Financial Reports, Union, 1932-1969 (Box 157, Folder 1)
- Financial Reports, Auditor's (Box 158, Folder 1)
- Financial Reports, Auditor's (Box 159, Folder 1)
- 1920's-1940's, correspondence, claims, etc.; documentation re black railroad workers (Box 160, Folder 1)
- BLF&E Magazine Dept. - A-P1 (Box 161, Folder 1)
- BLF&E Magazine Dept. - Po-Wa (Box 162, Folder 1)
- BLF&E Magazine Dept. - "Who's Who" A-Mc (Box 163, Folder 1)
- BLF&E Magazine Dept. - Who's Who" M-Z (Box 164, Folder 1)
- Amalgamation (Box 165, Folder 1)
- Featherbedding (Box 165, Folder 2)
- History of Electric Helper (Box 165, Folder 3)
- Metropolitan Transportation Authority (Box 165, Folder 4)
- Mooney, Tom (Box 165, Folder 5)
- Railpax (Box 165, Folder 6)
- Railway Labor Act and History of RLA (Box 165, Folder 7a-c)
- Railway Passenger Service, 1959 (Box 165, Folder 8)
- Strikes (Box 165, Folder 9)
- Lodge 1 - 997 (Box 166, Folder 1)
  (6 volumes in numerical order) re appeals, etc. Record of Membership by state Lodge 822 Minute book, 1913 Statistical data by lodge number (17 file folders)
- Additional statistical data on computer printout sheets (Box 167, Folder 1)
- Correspondence of Legislative Chairmen, 1929-1975 (Box 168, Folder 1)
- Additional Correspondence, alphabetical, G-Z, 1929-1964 (Box 169, Folder 1)
- Financial Reports; Minutes of Joint Meetings, 1920-1948 (Box 170, Folder 1)
  Minutes of Joint Meetings, 1920-34; Statewide Legislative Conference documents, 1946-47; State Belt Railroad; Jim Symes, United Labor Committee; Union Labor Party, 1948; United Labor Legislative Committee, 1943-
- Lodge 58 (Box 171, Folder 1)
- Lodge 91 (Box 171, Folder 2-3)
- Lodge 97 (Box 171, Folder 4)
- Lodge 139 (Box 171, Folder 5-8)
- Lodge 143 (Box 171, Folder 9-10)
- Lodge 239 (Box 171, Folder 11)
- Lodge 260 (Box 171, Folder 12)
- Lodge 312 (Box 171, Folder 13)
- Lodge 314 (Box 171, Folder 14)
- Lodge 327 (Box 171, Folder 15)
- Lodge 386 (Box 171, Folder 16)
- Lodge 566 (Box 171, Folder 17)
- Lodge 663 (Box 171, Folder 18)
- Lodge 672 (Box 171, Folder 19)
- Lodge 756 (Box 172, Folder 1-2)
- Lodge 794 (Box 172, Folder 3-5)
- Lodge 795 (Box 172, Folder 6-9)
- Lodge 808 (Box 172, Folder 10-17)
- Lodge 817 (Box 172, Folder 18-20)
- Lodge 820 (Box 172, Folder 21-22)
- Lodge 946 (Box 172, Folder 23)
- Lodge 967 (Box 172, Folder 24)
- Lodge 979 (Box 172, Folder 25)
- Lodge 1001 (Box 172, Folder 26)
- Air Hose Release Valve (Box 173, Folder 1)
- American Communications Association (Box 173, Folder 2)
- Application of the Federal Hours of Service Law (Box 173, Folder 3)
- Arizona Car Limit Bill (Box 173, Folder 4)
- Assembly Bill (Box 173, Folder 5)
- Atchison, Topeka & Santa Fe Railroad (Water Container Question) (Box 173, Folder 6)
- Bill (Legislative) (Box 173, Folder 7)
- BLF&E Convention, 1947 (Box 173, Folder 8)
- Burke, Garvin (Box 173, Folder 9)
- California Code Commission (Box 173, Folder 10)
- Circulars-Letters and Assessment Notices (Box 173, Folder 11-13)
- Conference Committee on Amalgamation (Box 173, Folder 14)
- Consolidation Committee of Enginemen (Box 173, Folder 15)
- General Wage Decrease (Box 173, Folder 16)